But this is the goal of my journey.
To reunite with my friend
who departed ten years ago.
Did you figure out where Gorilla went?
Tür.
It's a trading city in the middle
of the northern lands.
That's a long ways east from here.
It's in the opposite
direction from Äußerst.
Yeah.
Frieren, I came on this journey
to chase after Gorilla.
I know.
The sun's about to set.
Can't we wait until tomorrow
to make a decision?
I asked the village to lend us a cabin.
They said we can use it
however we want.
Thank you.
I got firewood.
I bought ingredients for dinner.
My hands are freezing.
It has gotten rather cold.
You're right.
Wow, this might be a new record.
Let me see.
You're right. They're really cold.
Right?
Don't!
Isn't this a new record?
Yeah. They're freezing.
Ridiculous.
It's snowing.
Will we need to wait
for winter to pass again?
We won't be crossing any
steep mountains this time.
Unless there's a serious blizzard,
we'll be fine.
It's blizzarding.
It sure is.
Yup.
In this region, cold waves
last an entire month.
I wouldn't recommend venturing far.
You can keep using the cabin for a while.
What do you want to do, Sein?
Should we leave?
Do you even need to ask?
So we're stuck here until
the cold wave passes.
That's what it sounds like.
But there are bars and shops here, at least.
This cabin's nice and large, too.
It's a lot better than the mountain cabin
we stayed in before.
And most importantly, there's a magic shop
in this village run by a shady old man.
In my experience, shops like those
tend to have legendary-level spells.
Getting to take my time
exploring it is a big win.
Legendary-level spells?
What kinds have you encountered so far?
A spell to get rid of mold
and a spell to remove tough oil stains.
Incredible.
Those spells are so convenient,
they changed my world.
They sound like a grandma's household wisdom.
In any case, the only thing
we can do now is wait.
We'll die if we underestimate
the winters of the northern lands.
Mr. Stark did nearly die
in the Schwer Mountains.
I'm from the northern lands.
I know that much.
Anyway, sounds like we'll be staying
together for a while longer.
The cold wave should be ending soon.
It won't be long before you adventurers
can finally continue on your journey.
Yeah, you're right.
Wait. Didn't we spend most of our time apart?
Sein.
Do you have a minute?
What is it, Frieren?
You don't often come to the tavern.
Stark and Fern are acting strange.
I think they're fighting.
Could you mediate?
Sure, but why are you asking me?
Because mediating is a priest's job.
Is it?
What a sorry state of affairs.
What happened here?
It's Mr. Stark's fault.
Yeah, it's all my fault.
We won't get anywhere like this.
Join me in the other room, one at a time.
So, what happened?
Remember how Fern touched my cheek
with her cold hands when we
first arrived at the cabin?
Yeah, I remember that.
Today, when I paid her back in kind,
she got upset.
What are you, a child?
Of course girls don't like it when
you put your hands on their face.
Are you okay with leaving
things the way they are?
I'd like to make up with her.
Stark. Unlike me, you're good at heart.
Be honest, and tell her how you feel.
If you want to make up,
then you have to tell her that.
Frieren won't mediate for you.
I know. I'll apologize to Fern.
Stark feels bad about what he did.
He's just a kid. He didn't mean any harm.
I know. I'm being stubborn.
I'd like to apologize to him.
It was my fault to begin with.
I don't mind that he touched me.
It's just... the arm he used to
restrain my shoulder was so strong.
It scared me a little.
Do you not like Stark?
Why would you ask that?
Is that how it seems to you?
Then tell him you were scared and make up.
Be gentler.
I'm sorry.
Just start dating already!
I'm not sure what happened,
but I think you're trying really hard, Sein.
Thanks for the help.
Frieren, you're the only one
who praises me like I'm a kid.
But you are a kid.
I guess it's not so bad.
You know, I've been wondering.
Why do you trouble yourself with me,
like when you invited me to travel with you?
Maybe it really is a dislike of my own kind.
The way you refused to go on an adventure
reminded me of myself before
I left to defeat the Demon King.
It made me angry.
That doesn't explain why you
concern yourself with me.
I think I wanted to give you a reason.
What does that mean?
It's what Himmel the Hero would've done.
Take my hand, Frieren.
I'll be your reason to go on a journey.
They gave me the courage to travel
and taught me the joy
of spending time with friends.
Well, Sein?
Haven't you had fun?
Yeah.
This has been a lot of fun.
I'm going to become
an unforgettable hero like Himmel.
I'm talking about the present, Sein.
So I decided to trust her words.
Gorilla talked about you a lot.
He said the two of you would become heroes
whose names would be remembered forever.
I've decided to go after Gorilla.
I won't live with regrets anymore.
I know.
Take care, then.
See you later.
Later.
Well, that was a quick goodbye.
Unlike you two, Sein is an adult.
I'm sure he'll be fine.
It's so quiet traveling alone.
Huh?
That's unusual. They're still asleep.
We've been walking a lot recently.
Maybe they're tired.
Good enough.
Hey, breakfast is ready. Get up.
Fern?
Frieren, wake up.
Just twelve more hours...
You can't sleep that long.
More importantly, Fern doesn't look well.
Hey.
Don't.
You've got a fever.
You need to keep warm and rest.
Let's see...
Huh? That's odd.
I brought water.
Found it.
What is that?
Sein left us some notes on medicinal herbs.
Sein did, huh?
I can use magic to identify her illness
and figure out which herbs to use.
But I thought identifying illnesses
was magic of the Goddess.
Didn't you say only the owner
of a holy scripture could cast it?
I've got a holy scripture.
What?
You're using it as a pot stand!
I'm not cut out to be a priest,
but even I can identify simple illnesses.
I can't identify complex ones, though.
You sure you're okay?
Yeah. It's just a cold.
Which of the applicable herbs
are found in this region?
Come to think of it,
there's a place nearby where I once
gathered herbs with Himmel and the others.
For now, let's head someplace
where we can get out of the cold.
You're right.
Oh?
You're a lifesaver.
I didn't think anyone lived
this deep in the mountains.
There was a whole village here
when I stopped by before.
That was decades ago.
It was a prestigious village
once visited by the hero.
Anyway, make yourselves at home.
Thank you.
By the way, isn't there an icicle
cherry blossom tree near here?
Yes, north of here.
It's a bit difficult to get there, though.
It's all right.
I've been here before.
Well, I'll be working.
Wait here, Fern.
We'll gather the ingredients
we need for your medicine.
You've been holding her hand
since we arrived.
Because she seems to be in pain.
When Fern has a cold,
holding her hand makes her feel better.
She's been that way since she was a child.
What's wrong?
Ms. Frieren, you're embarrassing me.
How?
Don't treat me like a child.
I see. You're right.
In two years, she'll be a full-grown adult.
It wasn't long ago that
she only came up to here.
I was way taller than her.
But in the blink of an eye, she grew up.
In my mind, Fern is still a child.
I'll probably always think of her that way.
Frieren...
We'd better hurry and get those herbs.
Yeah.
We should be arriving at the
icicle cherry blossom tree soon.
Is the icicle cherry blossom tree
the last ingredient we need for the medicine?
We'll actually be using the mushrooms
that grow at the base of the tree.
It's beautiful.
I wish we could've showed Fern.
It might be my favorite flower
that blooms in winter.
Be careful. The flowers are poisonous.
Hey, why'd you hold Fern's hand?
Normally you don't treat her
that much like a child.
I wasn't trying to treat her like a child.
I simply held her hand because
it looked like she was in pain.
It's the only way I know to relieve her pain.
What should I have done?
I guess you just have to do
what you want to do.
At least, that's what my master did.
People probably need emotional support.
Nobody dislikes receiving support.
What do you think you're doing?
You were moaning in your sleep.
We feel helpless when we're sick.
I lost my mother when I was young,
but she used to hold my hand like this.
It's strangely calming.
You mean when you were a child, right?
It's not just children who
need emotional support.
It doesn't bother you, does it?
You're right.
I guess it's not so bad.
I'm pretty handsome when
I'm being considerate, aren't I?
Please just be quiet.
The medicine is ready.
Fern was probably embarrassed
because I was there.
Nobody likes to be seen acting
like a pampered child.
Thank you, Stark.
I'll try doing what I want to do.
To thank you, I'll hold your hand
when you get sick.
Don't. It's embarrassing.
Okay, let's gather some mushrooms.
Hup.
They're bigger than I expected! Scary!
Now we just add the other ingredients...
And mix very, very well.
You're like a witch! Really scary!
Open your mouth, Fern.
You're good at that. Thanks for the help.
You think so?
It's all right. You'll feel better soon.
Ms. Frieren, I'm not a child anymore.
I know.
I know that.
Take care of yourselves!
Thank you so much!
You're looking a lot better.
I have the two of you and
Mr. Sein's notes to thank for that.
The owner of that home was very kind, too.
Okay.
Our destination is Äußerst, the city of magic.
Could I take a look at that?
Try it.
Maybe I'll take a break.
This year's test-takers
seem rather exceptional.
You wanna fight, huh?
I can't do this alone.
You have the eyes of a killer.
Don't call me an old mage.
Dunno.
The first-class mage exam will now begin.